KHASKHELI YOUSIF Ali

Mechanical Engineer
Cell No +966 583773829
E-mail yousifali81@yahoo.com
yousifali81@gmail.com
Skype yousifali81



SUMMARY

I am a dynamic engineer with experience more than 12 Years as a Mechanical Engineer Experience in Building Construction side. I have a genuine passion for engineering and a strong drive to be successful in my career. I have already gained a wide range of experience in my career and I enjoy the fact that every day is a new challenge .I have a technical background in the areas of design and assessment. Alongside this technical experience, I have also gained experience in project management and construction team management .I am now looking for the next challenge in any reputed company and available immediately. I believe that my skills would be an advantage to any MEP company, and I would welcome the opportunity to discuss any potential vacancies with you.

KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS

Good Knowledge of Mechanical Works in Building Construction Side In several Fields and Also In Maintenance.

Excellent written and verbal communication skills along with the strong interpersonal skills.

Good understanding of Quality Management System and QA/QC System from Project starts to final project dossier and familiar with various local/International codes and standards.

Ability to review document submittals and evaluate its integrity and compliance as per project drawings and specifications.

Skilled at handling multiple tasks simultaneously in challenging environments with excellent relationship. Ensure the work according to the BOQ and coordinates to all departments as well as with subcontractors.

Ability to review and monitor contractor's shop drawings, materials and method statements. Record changes on site and review As-Built drawings/submissions.

Ability to handle contractors claims, variation orders, change orders and interimpayment certificate.

EDUCATION

(Mechanical Engineering) 2006 Quaid-e-Awam Engineering University of Science & Technology Nawabshah, Sindh PAKISTAN

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATION

Pakistan Engineering Council PEC-Reg.No. Mech/249575 Saudi Engineering Council International SEC-249575

COMPUTER SKILL

AutoCAD2D, Ms Office, Ms Excel & Power point.

EMPLOYMENT AND EXPERIENCE

- Assistant Project Manager at AL-Hanouf Contracting Saudi Arabia in Abdullah Environment Echo Park AL-AHSA from September 2014 to till date & also working in Omran Hospital under the supervision of Ministry of Health.
- 2. SITE Mechanical Engineer at ENDECO Engineering Construction & Industrial Development Co Saudi Arabia in SAPIT-AL-ALAYA 100 bed hospital project finished

- and also worked in AL-BAHA Secondary College Project as Oct 2012 to Oct 2014. (02 Years)
- Mechanical Engineer at Engro Powergen Qadirpur Ltd Powerplant Ghotki, Sindh-Pakistan on 200 MW Combined cycle Power plant.
 May 2011-Septemper 2012 (01 Year & 4

May 2011-Septemper 2012 (01 Year & 4 months)

- Maintenance Engineer in SAUDI OGER KAUST Project JEDDAH Saudi Arabia (August 2009 to April 2011). (01 Year & 08 Months).
- Mechanical Engineer at Rohri Cement Pvt Ltd Sukkur, Sindh-Pakistan. June 2006-August 2009 (03 years & 2 Months).
- 6. 02 Months Internship at Pakistan Steel Mill Karachi, Sindh-Pakistan.

Worked with the focus of responsibility on execution of projects.

- Perform and Supervision of the project activities and check the progress as per profile.
- Profile of Pumps, Plumbing, HVAC, Fire Fighting, Irrigation System, Medical Gas, boilers, STO, RO, Vacuum & Compressors, LPG & STEAMPiping.
- Perform Compaction test of different layers sub grade & base course.
- Monitor project progress to ensure conformity with approved schedule, engineering/ project standards, specifications & designs. Make recommendations where extra resource or alternative work processes are required to maintain or increase performance.
- Co-ordinate with Management, Consultants & Sub Contractors.
- Ensure Safety best practices are being utilized during all site activities.
- Review the Tender & Shop Drawings, BOQ & Specification.

PROJECTINVOLVEDINTHE CONSTRUCTION As Well As MAINTENANCE

Mechanical Engineer in ROHRI Cement (June 2006 to August 2009).

SAUDI OGER Company in KAUST Project as Maintenance Engineer (August 2009 to April 2011) Under the supervision of Saudi Aramco.

230 MW combined cycle power plant Engro Energy Ghotki (May 2011 to September 2012).

ENDECO Engineering Construction & Industrial Development Co Saudi Arabia (Oct 2012 to Oct 2014) under the supervision of Ministry of health & Ministry of Education.

AL-HANOUF Contracting Saudi Arabia (September 2014 totill date).

Attended Safety Trainings ISO 9002 in SAUDI OGER.

Worked with the focus of responsibility Various projects of construction & maintenance.

- Supervised all mechanical works regarding to MEP works Installation and maintenance.
- Checking the Quality of Construction Material brought at Site.
- > As per Specifications, Infrastructure Works.
- Works and Site Development etc.
- Make sure that CONTRACTOR has submitted the Method Statement (MS), Quality Control (QCP) and Inspection & Test Plan.
- Testing &Commissioning.
- Review shop drawings, As-built drawings related to discipline, and ensure its compliance with design requirements, contract requirements, properly coordinated with other disciplines and submitted as per the approved schedules.
- Review and approval of Materials, ensuring compliance with contract

requirements and submitted as per approved Projectschedule.

THESIS PROJECT

ROBOTIC ARM

Worked with the focus of responsibility on execution of construction projects.

- Working on Water supply, Waste Water components.
- Working on Pumps (Irrigation, Fire Fighting, HVAC).
- Working on Piping for Chilled Water, Steam Piping, Medical Gas, LPG.
- Installations of FCUs, AHUs, Boilers, Chillers, Compressors.
- > Installations of Ro Plants and Stp.
- > Exercised functional authority for control and completion of projects.
- Actively initiate the schedule, plan the required resources, set the construction logistics, Quality and safety plans and enforced of the same, perform follow up, analysis and monitoring activities.
- Installation and alignment of Gas Turbine, generator, Exhaust, Auxiliary.
- Installation of Over Head Crane of GT and ST.
- Installation of Gas turbine, Generator and Auxiliary.
- > Installation of Instrument air compressor.
- Installation of overhead crane at (GT, ST, Workshop and store).
- Installation of Pumps, Boiler, Presser Vessels and related Parameters Prepare of look ahead program, cash flow management, submittals, shop drawings, variations/ claims, Established and maintained effective QA/QC system in place for the Projects strictly adhering to standards and specifications.

KNOWLEDGE OF LANGUAGES

English, Urdu, Sindhi & Arabic.

HOBBIES

Reading Books, Playing Cricket & Internet Browsing.

Reference

Available upon request.